A Register of the Albert J. and Roberta Wohlstetter Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Roberta Wohlstetter File, 1933-1996.; See also Speeches and Writings for writings and studies co-authored with Albert Wohlstetter (Box 355)
  - Conferences, 1935-1993.
    - "Intelligence and the Avoidance of Surprise," presentation, Institute of International Studies, University of California, Berkeley, 1964 May 15. (Folder 362: 6)
    - "Kidnapping to Win Friends and Influence People," paper, California Seminar on Arms Control and Foreign Policy, 1973 September 11?
      - General (Folder 362: 7)
      - Notes (with Albert Wohlstetter)? (Folder 362: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 362: 9-14)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 363: 1)
    - "The Buddha Smiles: Absentminded Aid and the Indian Bomb," paper, California Seminar on Arms Control and Foreign Policy, 1976 November 18
      - General (Folder 363: 2)
      - Background materials (Folder 363: 3)
      - Notes (Folder 363: 4)
      - Typescript (Folder 363: 5-8)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 364: 1-4)
    - "U.S. Peaceful Aid and the Indian Bomb," paper, California Seminar on Arms Control and Foreign Policy, 1976 December. (Folder 364: 5)
    - "Warning and no Response," speech, Senior Intelligence Officers Conference, United States Air Force, Florida, 1985 April 2-4
      - General (Folder 364: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 364: 7)
  - Conversation transcripts., See Speeches
  - Correspondence, 1935-1993.
    - General
      - General (Folder 364: 8)
      - A-Y (Folder 364: 9)
    - Unidentified (Folder 364: 10)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1965 (Box-folder 365: 1)
    - American Broadcasting Company, 1964 (Folder 365: 2)
    - American Political Science Review, 1970 (Folder 365: 3)
    - American Studies Film Center, Inc., 1990-1991 (Folder 365: 4)
    - Asada, Sadao, 1969 (Folder 365: 5)
    - Betancourt, Ernesto, 1965.; See also Pan American Union (Folder 365: 6)
    - Biehl, Clarissa Whitney, 1972 (Folder 365: 7)
    - Blackman, W. W., Inc., 1956 (Folder 365: 8)
    - Brody, Richard, 1993 (Folder 365: 9)
    - Brookings Institution, 1962-1963 (Folder 365: 10)
    - Bull, Hedley, 1965 (Folder 365: 11)
    - Campo, Ricardo del, 1964 (Folder 365: 12)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1961-1966 (Folder 365: 13)
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies, Georgetown University, 1978-1987 (Folder 365: 14)
    - Cline, Ray S., 1964 (Folder 365: 15)
    - Colegio Nacional de Taquigrafos de Cuba en el Exilio (Cuban Stenographers Association in Exile), 1963-1965 (Folder 365: 16)
    - Columbia University, 1935-1969 (Folder 365: 17)
    - Columbia University Law School, 1954 (Folder 365: 18)
    - Comité pro Libertad de Cuba, 1964 (Folder 365: 19)
    - Committee for the Free World, n.d. (Folder 365: 20)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1963-1992 (Folder 365: 21)
    - Council on Religion and International Affairs, 1964 (Folder 365: 22)
    - CUBA, 1962-1963 (Folder 365: 23)
    - Cuban Freedom Committee, 1965 (Folder 365: 24)
    - Cyclopedia of Literary and Dramatic Criticism, 1942 (Folder 365: 25)
    - Davis, Paul, 1962 (Folder 365: 26)
    - Despres, Leon M., Mrs., n.d. (Folder 365: 27)
    - Diario de las Americas, 1964 (Folder 365: 28)
    - Dictionary of Literary and Dramatic Criticism, 1942 (Folder 365: 29)
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1964 (Folder 365: 30)
    - Drake, Sylvia, 1967. (Folder 365: 31)
      Includes letter from Ladislas Farago
    - Draper, Theodore, 1962-1966 (Folder 365: 32)
    - Dudik, Evan M., 1980 (Folder 365: 33)
    - Dwight D. Eisenhower Library, 1991 (Folder 365: 34)
    - Dyer, George C., 1957 (Folder 365: 35)
    - Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1962 (Folder 365: 36)
    - Eliot House, 1940-1941 (Folder 365: 37)
    - European American Institute for Security Research, 1983-1988 (Folder 365: 38)
    - Fernandez, Angel V., 1964 (Folder 365: 39)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1965-1983 (Folder 365: 40)
    - Frangie, J. J., 1956 (Folder 365: 41)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt Library, 1956 (Folder 365: 42)
    - Friedenberg, Daniel M., 1963 (Folder 365: 43)
    - Friedman, William F., 1956 (Folder 365: 44)
    - Friends of the Santa Monica Public Library, 1963-1965. (Folder 365: 45)
      Includes a letter from Donald H. Hunt to J. M. Goldsen
    - Fubini, ?, 1963 (Folder 365: 46)
    - Gabor, Dennis and Marjorie, 1965 (Folder 365: 47)
    - Griswold, Erwin N., 1956 (Folder 365: 48)
    - Haggarty, James, 1963 (Folder 365: 49)
    - Harper & Row, Publishers, 1963 (Folder 365: 50)
    - Harris, Stanley G., Jr., 1967 (Folder 365: 51)
    - Harvard University, 1941-1967, including Division of Modern Languages and Center for International Affairs. (Folder 365: 52)
      Includes a letter to McGeorge Bundy from the United States Supreme Court, and to Felix Frankfurter from McGeorge Bundy
    - History of the United States Naval Operations in World War II, 1961 (Folder 365: 53)
    - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1964-1984 (Folder 365: 54)
    - Hornbeck, Stanley K., 1964-1965 (Folder 365: 55)
    - Huddleson, Edwin E., Jr., 1957 (Folder 365: 56)
    - Huertas, Enrique, 1965 (Folder 365: 57)
    - Imperial College of Science and Technology, 1965 (Box-folder 366: 1)
    - Institute for Defense Analyses, 1968 (Folder 366: 2)
    - Institute of Contemporary History, 1965-1976 (Folder 366: 3)
    - Instituto para la Educacion Politica, 1963 (Folder 366: 4)
    - International Institute for Strategic Studies Ltd., 1965-1986 (Folder 366: 5)
    - International Journal, 1968 (Folder 366: 6)
    - Istituto Affari Internazionali, 1980-1982 (Folder 366: 7)
    - ITEK Laboratories, 1963 (Folder 366: 8)
    - J.P. Tarcher, Inc., 1965 (Folder 366: 9)
    - Jackson, Henry M., 1964 (Folder 366: 10)
    - Jervis, Robert, 1965 (Folder 366: 11)
    - Johns Hopkins University, 1939-1940 (Folder 366: 12)
    - Jones, Howard, 1940-1942.; See also Harvard University (Folder 366: 13)
    - Journal of English Literary History, 1939 (Folder 366: 14)
    - Journal of Modern History, 1965 (Folder 366: 15)
    - Kozolchyk, Boris, 1967. (Folder 366: 16)
      Includes letter by Córdova, Efrén
    - Leites, Nathan, 1967-1969. (Folder 366: 17)
      Includes letters by others
    - Little, David, 1969 (Folder 366: 18)
    - Loomis, ?, 1967 (Folder 366: 19)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1965-1986 (Folder 366: 20)
    - McCollum, A. H., 1956-1967. (Folder 366: 21)
      Includes a letter to Harry Elmer Barnes
    - Macmillan Company, 1962-1965 (Folder 366: 22)
    - Marder, ?, 1965 (Folder 366: 23)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1965 (Folder 366: 24)
    - Mederos de Gonzáles, Elena, 1965 (Folder 366: 25)
    - Metz, William D., 1979 (Folder 366: 26)
    - National Broadcasting Company, 1964-1983 (Folder 366: 27)
    - National War College, 1963 (Folder 366: 28)
    - Nehemkis, Peter R., Jr., 1965 (Folder 366: 29)
    - New Yorker, 1963 (Folder 366: 30)
    - Norwegian Defence Research Establishment, 1986-1987 (Folder 366: 31)
    - Occidental College, 1965 (Folder 366: 32)
    - Ormsby, Charles, 1981-1983 (Folder 366: 33)
    - Oxford University Press, 1939-1962 (Folder 366: 34)
    - Palliser, A. M., 1965 (Folder 366: 35)
    - Pan American Union, 1965-1969 (Folder 366: 36)
    - Pazos, ?, 1965 (Folder 366: 37)
    - Pearl Harbor Project, 1987-1991 (Folder 366: 38)
    - Philological Quarterly, 1940 (Folder 366: 39)
    - Pineau, Roger, 1962 (Folder 366: 40)
    - Pomona College, 1964 (Folder 366: 41)
    - Princeton University Press, 1959-1965. (Folder 366: 42)
      Includes a letter from Princeton University Center of International Studies to Bernard ? regarding the Wohlstetters and a letter to the Rand Corporation
    - Purdue University, 1967 (Folder 366: 43)
    - Quijano, Carlos, 1963 (Folder 366: 44)
    - Racquet Club of Palm Springs, California, n.d. (Folder 366: 45)
    - Random House, Inc., 1966-1970 (Folder 366: 46)
    - Réplica, 1964 (Folder 366: 47)
    - Reporter, 1954 (Folder 366: 48)
    - Research Analysis Corporation, 1965 (Folder 366: 49)
    - Revolución, 1963 (Folder 366: 50)
    - Ross, Frank S., 1963 (Folder 366: 51)
    - Rossant,?, 1974 (Folder 366: 52)
    - Rousselot, Peter, 1964 (Folder 366: 53)
    - Ryan, Paul B., 1981. (Folder 366: 54)
      Includes letter by James A. Carr
    - San Diego State College, 1967 (Folder 366: 55)
    - Seidman & Seidman, 1965-1978 (Folder 366: 56)
    - Shipley, ?, 1942 (Folder 366: 57)
    - Slater, Joseph, 1963 (Folder 366: 58)
    - Sonnenfeldt, Helmut, 1966 (Folder 366: 59)
    - Spencer, ?, 1941 (Folder 366: 60)
    - Stanford Research Institute, 1961 (Folder 366: 61)
    - Stanford University, 1962-1964 (Folder 366: 62)
    - Stanford University Press, 1963-1968.; See Writings
    - Stiftung Wissenschaft und Politik, 1980 (Folder 366: 63)
    - Swearingen, Rodger, 1968 (Folder 366: 64)
    - Texas Parks and Wildlife Department, 1990 (Folder 366: 65)
    - Thapar, Romila, 1966 (Folder 366: 66)
    - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1973 (Folder 366: 67)
    - United States. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1976 (Folder 366: 68)
    - United States. Congress. House of Representatives, 1964 (Folder 366: 69)
    - United States. General Services Administration, 1956-1965 (Folder 366: 70)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1963-1964 (Folder 366: 71)
    - University of California, Davis, 1965 (Folder 366: 72)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, 1965 (Folder 366: 73)
    - University of California, Santa Cruz, 1965-1966 (Folder 366: 74)
    - University of Southern California, 1968 (Folder 366: 75)
    - Vassar College, 1938-1962. (Folder 366: 76)
      Includes a letter to Luigi Einaudi
    - Volsky, George, 1964-1965 (Folder 366: 77)
    - Watson, J. H. A., 1965 (Folder 366: 78)
    - World Affairs Council of Northern California, 1963 (Folder 366: 79)
    - World Affairs Council of the Monterey Peninsula, 1963 (Folder 366: 80)
    - Wurtele, M. G., n.d. (Folder 366: 81)
    - Yost, David, 1985 (Folder 366: 82)
  - Interviews, 1961-1979 (Box 367)
    - Carlos Quijano and Matos officers, Undated (Folder 367: 1)
    - Bernard Relin, Raul Chibas, Park F. Wollam, Ernesto Betancourt, and John Topping, 1961 (Folder 367: 2)
    - Sanchez Arango, Maria Llerena, Antonio Carrera, and Carlos Garcia, 1962-1964 (Folder 367: 3)
    - James L. Holloway, III., 1979 February 1 (Folder 367: 4)
      Includes holograph notes and related materials
  - Letter to the editor of Saturday Evening Post, 1963 January 14, commenting on the publication of the condensed version of the novel Fail-Safe by Eugene Burdick and Harvey Wheeler. (Folder 367: 5)
  - Notes, 1973-1995.
    - General (Folder 367: 6-7)
    - Untitled
      - General (Folder 367: 8)
      - On Naples-Crowe visit (Folder 367: 9)
      - On Nordic Flank (Folder 367: 10)
      - On Pershing II (Folder 367: 11)
      - On signals sanctions (with Arthur?) (Folder 367: 12)
    - "Iran-Turkey Relations and the Ethnic Minority Problems" (Folder 367: 13)
    - "Notes on Ranks" (Folder 367: 14)
    - "Notes on Signals Hidden in Noise" (Folder 367: 15)
    - "Schwarzopf, It Doesn't Take a Hero" (Folder 367: 16)
  - Printed matter, 1958-1990 (Box-folder 368: 1-2)
  - Research materials, 1958-1983.
    Includes clippings and printed matter, correspondence, lists, notes (with others), papers by others, reports, and speeches by others
    - Central America (Folder 368: 3)
    - Cuba (Folder 368: 4-8)
    - Cuba (Box 369-371)
    - Cuba (Box-folder 372: 1-5)
    - Germany (Folder 372: 6)
    - India (Folder 372: 7-14)
    - Latin America (Folder 372: 15-16)
    - Latin America (Box-folder 373: 1-2)
  - Speeches, 1968-1988.
    Includes conference calls and conversations. Typescript unless otherwise noted
    - Talk with Goldy?, n.d. (Folder 373: 3)
    - Speech on nuclear terror, Williamsburg, Virginia, n.d. (Folder 373: 4)
    - "From Hemisphere Defense to Internal War," talk, Council on Religion and International Affairs (CRIA), 1968 November
      - Background materials (Folder 373: 5)
      - Notes (Folder 373: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 373: 7)
    - Conversation with Fred Ikle on discouraging and living with the spread of nuclear weapons, Washington, D.C., 1975 July 4
      - Background materials (Folder 373: 8)
      - Notes (Folder 373: 9)
    - Conference call with ACDA, 1976 March
      - Notes (with Albert Wohlstetter)? (Folder 373: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 373: 11)
    - "Surprised by the Obvious," speech, National Press Club, 1988 December 7
      - Background materials (Folder 373: 12)
      - Notes (Folder 373: 13)
      - Typescript (Folder 373: 14)
  - United States government service file, 1955-1991
    - Los Alamos National Laboratory, 1985. (Folder 373: 15)
      Letter to Gregory Canavan
    - U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, 1975-1983. (Folder 373: 16)
      Correspondence
    - United States. Air Force, 1955-1984
      - General (Folder 373: 17)
      - Correspondence, including with Roberta Wohlstetter (Folder 373: 18)
      - Study, "Pearl Harbor – Indicators of Soviet Intentions" by Roberta Wohlstetter (Folder 373: 19)
    - United States. Army, 1956-1986
      - Correspondence, including with Roberta Wohlstetter (Folder 373: 20)
      - List (Folder 373: 21)
    - United States. Defense Nuclear Agency (DNA)., See also PanHeuristics
      - Correspondence (Folder 373: 22)
      - Memoranda (Folder 373: 23)
      - Reports., See PanHeuristics
    - United States. Department of Defense (DOD), 1948-1991
      - General
        - General (Folder 373: 24)
        - Correspondence (Folder 373: 25)
        - Lists (Folder 373: 26)
        - Memoranda (Folder 373: 27)
        - Printed matter (Folder 373: 28)
        - Security clearance file (Folder 373: 29)
      - Defense Science Board (DSB) (Box 374)
        - General (Folder 374: 1)
        - Correspondence (Folder 374: 2)
        - Lists (Folder 374: 3)
        - Memoranda (Folder 374: 4)
          including to Roberta Wohlstetter
      - Miscellany (Folder 374: 5)
    - United States. Department of State, 1962-1970
      - Correspondence and memoranda (Folder 374: 6)
      - Conference program (Folder 374: 7)
    - United States. Energy Research and Development Administration (ERDA). Letter from Julio L. Torres., See also Career File/PanHeuristics (Folder 374: 8)
    - United States. Navy, 1977-1991. (Folder 374: 9)
  - Writings, 1939-1988.; See also Speeches and Writings
    - General
      - Berlin. (Folder 374: 10)
      - Cuba, assorted writings, n.d. (Folder 374: 11-17)
        Includes some dated materials. Holograph and typescript
      - Cuba, assorted writings, n.d. (Box 375)
      - Cuba, assorted writings, n.d. (Box-folder 376: 1-3)
      - Japan, by Roberta Wohlstetter?, n.d. (Folder 376: 4)
      - Treaty of Versailles (1919), n.d. (Folder 376: 5)
    - "The Gentle Art of Journalism in the Mooney-Billings Case," n.d., review of a summary of information presented in the Wickersham report and in What Happened in the Mooney Case, by Ernest Jerome Hopkins. (Folder 376: 6)
    - "Raisuli Alive," by Roberta Wohlstetter?, n.d. (Folder 376: 7)
    - "Responses during a Crisis: The Cuban Case," by Roberta Wohlstetter?, n.d. (Folder 376: 8)
    - Review of Persian Painting: 12 Colour Plates, with an introduction by Basil Gray, n.d. (Folder 376: 9)
    - "Slow Pearl Harbors and the Pleasures of Self-Deception," (Folder 376: 10)
    - Strategic Air Command (SAC) (Folder 376: 11)
    - "U.S Peaceful Aid and the Indian Bomb,", See Conferences
    - Review of Roger Fry, "Last Lectures,", 1939 November 18. (Folder 376: 12)
    - Review of The Notebooks of Leonardo da Vinci, 1939 November 24. (Folder 376: 13)
    - "The Philosophic Basis of Coleridge's Hamlet Criticism," A Journal of English Literary History, 1939 December. (Folder 376: 14)
    - Review of Kenneth Clark, "Leonardo da Vinci: An Account of His Development as an Artist,", 1940 February 3. (Folder 376: 15)
    - "Some Stoic Lines in Hamlet and the Problem of Interpretation," Philosophical Quarterly, 1941 October. (Folder 376: 16)
    - Comments to Jacques Sadoul's letters to Albert Thomas on the Bolshevik revolution, 1951 October 26. (Folder 376: 17)
    - Pearl Harbor: Warning and Decision, 1962 (Box 377)
      - General (Folder 377: 1)
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - Undated (Folder 377 :2)
          - 1954-1987 (Folder 377 :3-9)
        - Stanford University Press (Box-folder 378: 1-5)
      - Memoranda (Folder 378: 6-7)
      - Notes (Folder 378: 8)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 379: 1-5)
      - Galleys (Folder 379: 6)
      - Printed copy (Folder 379: 7)
      - Reviews. (Folder 379: 8)
        Includes letters to the editors
      - Reviews. (Box 380)
        Includes lists of reviews
      - Reviews (Box-folder 381: 1)
      - Telegrams (Folder 381: 2)
      - Writings by others (Folder 381: 3)
    - "When Is a Signal not a Signal or the Perils of Monday Morning Quarterbacking,", 1963 July 23. (Folder 381: 4)
    - "Notes on Castro and Oswald: The Maximom Lider on the Assassination,", 1964 February
      - Background materials (Folder 381: 5)
      - Notes (Folder 381: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 381: 7)
    - "Signals before Pearl Harbor and before the Cuban Missile Crisis,", 1964 May 11. (Folder 381: 8)
    - "Little War in a Great Shadow: Ties of Castro's Insurrection to the United States,", 1964 December
      - Notes (Folder 381: 9)
      - Typescript (Folder 381: 10-11)
    - "Cuba and Pearl Harbor: Hindsight and Foresight," Foreign Affairs, 1965 July
      - Correspondence (Folder 381: 12)
      - Notes (Folder 381: 13)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 382: 1-4)
      - Printed copies (Folder 382: 5)
    - "Sunday, December 7, 1941, and the Monday Morning Quarterbacks," Air Force, 1966 December. (Folder 382: 6)
      Printed copy. Includes galleys and related materials
    - "Two Security Systems: A Note on Batista and Castro,", 1968 September 10. (Folder 382: 7)
    - Comments on Edward Gonzales, "D-18834-ISA Castro's Troubled Revolution,", 1969 July 3. (Folder 382: 8)
    - Comments on Nathan Leites' manuscript and its possible policy implications, 1970 January 22 (Box 383)
      - Notes (Folder 383: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 383: 2)
    - "Administration and Compensation Procedures for Twentieth Century Fund Projects,", 1974 April. (Folder 383: 3)
    - International Terrorism: Kidnapping to Win Friends and Influence People," Survey, 1974 Autumn
      - Typescript (Folder 383: 4)
      - Printed copy (Folder 383: 5)
      - Reviews (Folder 383: 6)
    - "Nuclear Terror,", 1976 April
      - Background materials (Folder 383: 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 383: 8)
      - Galley (Folder 383: 9)
    - "Summary of India,", 1976 May 15
      - Correspondence (Folder 383: 10)
      - Notes (Folder 383: 11)
      - Typescript (Folder 383: 12-15)
      - Typescript (Box-folder 384: 1-3)
    - "Terror on a Grand Scale," Survival, 1976 May-June. (Folder 384: 4)
    - "The Buddha Smiles: Absent-Minded Peaceful Aid and the Indian Bomb, 1977 April 30.; See Career file/PanHeuristics
    - "The Pleasures of Self-Deception," Washington Quarterly, 1979 Autumn. (Folder 384: 5)
    - "Preliminary Conclusions on Warning for Power Projection,", 1981 April 26. (Folder 384: 6)
    - Suggestions for use by Fred Ikle for his testimony, 1983 March. (Folder 384: 7)
    - "On Arms Control,", 1984 August. (Folder 384: 8)
    - Untitled, 1988 December 7. (Folder 384: 9)
  - Miscellany (Folder 384: 10)
- CLOSED (Box 385-754)
- Printed Matter, 1933-1997. (Box 755)
  Bibliographies, bulletins, clippings, conference proceedings, journals, newsletters, pamphlets, publications, reports, serial issues, textbooks, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Bibliographies, 1952-1968 (Folder 755: 1-2)
  - Bulletins, 1962-1993 (Folder 755: 3-4)
  - Clippings, 1958-1995 (Folder 755: 5-6)
  - Clippings, 1958-1995 (Box 756-759)
  - Clippings, 1958-1995 (Box-folder 760: 1-2)
  - Conference proceedings, 1968-1996 (Folder 760: 3-6)
  - Journals, 1933-1996 (Box 761-770)
  - Magazines, 1961-1997 (Box 771-772)
  - Newsletters, 1963-1997 (Box 773-774)
  - Newsletters, 1963-1997 (Box-folder 775: 1-4)
  - Newspapers, 1951-1994 (Folder 775: 5-6)
  - Newspapers, 1951-1994 (Box 776-778)
  - Publications (Box 779-790)
    - General, 1947-1997
    - United States government, 1941-1996 (Box 791-794)
      - General
      - Congress (Box 795-801)
  - Reports (Box 802-808)
  - Studies, 1944-1997 (Box 809-811)
  - Studies, 1944-1997 (Box-folder 812: 1-4)
  - Textbooks (Folder 812: 5-6)
- Photographs, 1964-1995. (Box 813)
  Prints, postcards, and slides depicting Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter, Ronald Reagan, Vlacav Havel, Adml. Chester W. Nimitz, and others
  - One print depicting Roberta Wohlstetter (as a student at Columbia University?), n.d. (Folder 813: 1)
  - Two prints depicting Albert Wohlstetter, n.d. (Folder 813: 2)
  - One print depicting Albert Wohlstetter (third from left) looking at the scale model of a housing design for Goodyear Aircraft, n.d., and one print depicting him (fourth from the right) in a group (Folder 813: 3)
  - One print depicting Albert Wohlstetter at home, n.d., and one print depicting Roberta Wohlstetter with Helen Morgan (Folder 813: 4)
  - One print depicting Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter on the occasion of their wedding, 1939. (Folder 813: 5)
    Photograph of wedding party includes Edmund M. Morgan, Edmund S. Morgan, Elsie Morgan, Helen Morgan, and Nellie Friedman
  - Three prints depicting Albert and Robert Wohlstetter in Mexico, 1940 (Folder 813: 6)
  - Two matching prints, in one frame, each depicting Roberta and Albert Wohlstetter, earlier one taken by Irving Lerner, 1954, and the later one taken at the time of Festschift (Folder 813: 7)
  - Six prints, with four including Albert Wohlstetter, taken at conferences of the Scientific Advisory Group Effects (SAGE), 1976-1981 (Folder 813: 8)
  - Two prints depicting Roberta and Albert Wohlstetter with Ronald Reagan at the White House during the Medal of Freedom award ceremony, 1985, and with an inscription by Reagan (Folder 813: 9)
  - Seventeen prints depicting Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter at a conference in Japan, 1992 (Folder 813: 10)
  - Four prints, two depicting Czech musicians, and two depicting Vaclav Havel, taken during the Wohlstetters' trip to Prague, 1990 (Folder 813: 11)
  - One print depicting Lix and Conrad Vetterli, Zurich, 1964 May (Folder 813: 12)
  - One print depicting Samuel Eliot Morison in Japan, 1963 (Folder 813: 13)
  - Three reconnaissance photographs depicting sites in Kuwait, 1987 (Folder 813: 14)
  - One print depicting destroyed Iraqi armored vehicles, 1991(?). (Folder 813: 15)
    Includes typescript list entitled, "41 Targets in Downtown Baghdad"
  - Fourteen prints depicting a Serbian MIG-21 aircraft in action over Bosnia and Herzegovina, and three prints depicting a map of Bosnia and Herzegovina, all taken from a broadcast news video, 1995 (Folder 813: 16)
  - One print depicting Admiral Chester W. Nimitz, n.d. (Folder 813: 17)
  - One print depicting Capt. Byran W. Compton, n.d. (Folder 813: 18)
  - One print depicting Capt. James H. Mauldin, n.d. (Folder 813: 19)
  - Fifty-one transparencies depicting various geopolitical situations, as viewed by American strategists, n.d. (Folder 813: 20)
  - Ten prints depicting U.S. Navy aircraft and carrier (Folder 813: 21)
  - Thirteen prints depicting model homes (pre-fabricated housing) for General Panel Corporation, California, n.d. (Folder 813: 22)
  - Three prints depicting designs for quilted cushions, n.d. (Folder 813: 23)
    Includes letter from Laurel Airica (formerly Judi Bloomberg), secretary to Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter in late 1970s?